Register to The David Stanley Smith Papers
Yale University Library
- Music, I
  - Miscellaneous works, I.J
    - Exercises (Box 28, Folder 331)
      - Examination tests for fellowship A.G.O., [2] p. of music; 35 cm.
        Contents: Ground bass with three solutions and code (11-29-42) -- Trio (to be used at sight.)
      - Exercises in XVIth century counterpoint 1939-1940 (Sketches) 1940 Mar 27, 22 p. of music, bound; 21 x 24 cm.
    - Juvenilia (Box 29)
      These works were in an envelope headed: Juvenilia with apologies for youthful sins and bad manuscript.
      Holograph list laid in.
      All holographs unless otherwise indicated.
      Contains:
      - "Alhambra" waltzes: for piano 1897 Feb (Box 29, Folder 332)
      - Asahel march-two step: for piano (Box 29, Folder 333)
      - Boulevard two-step: for piano 1896 Dee (Box 29, Folder 334)
      - Charity ball twostep: for piano 1896 Dec (Box 29, Folder 335)
      - "Cradle-song": for string orchestra 1896 Apr (Box 29, Folder 336)
      - La débutante waltz: for piano 1896 Dec (Box 29, Folder 337)
      - Gavotte: for piano 1893 Sep 26 (Box 29, Folder 338)
      - I'm the hottest nigger on the map: coon song (Box 29, Folder 339)
      - I wandered lonely: song for medium voice 1905 Jun 30 (Box 29, Folder 340)
      - My Sue: for voice and piano (Box 29, Folder 341)
      - "Olympian" two-step: for piano 1896 Jan 30 (Box 29, Folder 342)
      - Piano piece 1911 Jun 6 (Box 29, Folder 343)
      - "Polly" or "Eyes of old Yale blue": solo for soprano or tenor in E flat (Box 29, Folder 344)
      - Romanza for violin 1896 Mar (Box 29, Folder 345)
      - Serenade: for mezzo-soprano 1897 Jan 14 (Box 29, Folder 346)
        Piano acc.
      - She walks in beauty: for voice and piano 1893 Sep (Box 29, Folder 347)
      - Sixth Ohio: for piano. -- Toledo: D.M. Caughling. 1898 (Box 29, Folder 348)
      - Symphonic adagio / Edward Grieg; arr. for orchestra by David Stanley Smith 1899 (Box 29, Folder 349)
      - Tattered classics: for ? (Box 29, Folder 350)
        Cover only
      - Tempo de valse: for piano 1895 Jan (Box 29, Folder 351)
      - Touchdown two step: for piano (Box 29, Folder 352)
      - Waltz: for piano (Box 29, Folder 353)
      - "Yale '99" march: for piano. -- Chicago: Lyon Healy. 1896 (Box 29, Folder 354)
    - Lists
      Lists of compositions of David Stanley Smith.
      Several lists, both manuscript and typescript, including a spiral notebook with list prepared by his wife, Cora W. Smith. These include opus numbers, publishers, dates of publication, and dates, performers, and places of performances.
      - Lists, 1 notebook + approx. 186 p. of loose and variously grouped sheets; various sizes. (Box 29, Folder 355-359)
      - Lists of music by others from David Stanley Smith's library 1950 Oct 5, 4 lists ([17], [6], 9, 10 p.); 28 cm. (Box 29, Folder 360)
        Manuscript in pencil and typescript.
      - List of music by others from David Stanley Smith's library found with this collection in 1981. (Box 29, Folder 362)
    - Sketches (Box 29, Folder 361)
      - Sketchbook, Loose sheets ([30] p. of music) various sizes.
        Holographs in pencil and ink.
        Contents: Blessed are they that hunger and thirst after righteousness -- Concerto -- The delicate air (1940 Jul 2) -- Organ finale -- Piano piece -- Russian carols -- Violin sonata -- Unidentified sketches.
      - Miscellaneous unidentified sketches, pieces, and fragments of pieces., Loose sheets (53 p. of music.)
    - Works by others
      Music by others from David Stanley Smith's library found with this collection in 1981.
      - Ballade (violin and piano) -- New York: 1915., Baumgartner, H. Leroy; 1 score (13 p.) + 1 part; 31 cm. (Box 29, Folder 362)
        Inscribed to David Stanley Smith by composer, 1926 Jan 12.
      - Romance (violin and piano) -- New York: 1915., Baumgartner, H. Leroy; 1 score (13 p.) + 1 part; 31 cm. (Box 29, Folder 362)
      - Sonata in G minor (organ) -- New York: 1913., Jepson, Harry Benjamin; 35 p. of music; 31 cm. (Box 29, Folder 363)
        Inscribed to David Stanley Smith by composer.
      - A wanderer's psalm: (cantus perigrinus) set to music for soli, chorus, and orchestra. -- London: 1900., Parker, Horatio; 1 vocal score (112 p.); 26 cm. (Box 29, Folder 364)
        Inscribed to David Stanley Smith by composer, 1900 Oct.
      - Sonata pour violon et piano -- Paris: 1927., Shepherd, Arthur; 1 score (38 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 365)
        Inscribed to David Stanley Smith by composer, 1928 Sep 4.
      - Benedic anima mea, Smith, W.H. [David Stanley Smith's father]; 1 vocal score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 29, Folder 366)
- Correspondence, II
  This series is divided into letters to and from Smith and others. It is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - To David Stanley Smith or Mrs. Smith from others 1913-1958, II.A
    Includes letters from Nadia Boulanger, Carl Engel, Ossip Gabrilowitsch, Howard Hanson, Arthur Shepherd, Bruce Simonds, Ralph Vaughan Williams, and Bruno Walter as well as from others.
    - Aldrich, Richard 1931 Jan. 14, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - American Academy in Rome 1928-1947, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - American Composers Alliance 1950 Mar. 21, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Angell, James Rowland 1921-1937, 7 items. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Aranha, Antonio B. Martins 1951 Jan. 11, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Balaban, Emanuel 1930 Jan. 28, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Ballantine, Edward 1946 Mar. 21, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Barney, Laura D. no year Dec. 5, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Bartlett, Ellen Strong 1935 Dec. 13, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Baumgartner, Hope Leroy 1950 Nov. 13, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Bellamann, Henry 1931-1932, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Berkeley College (Yale University) 1941 Dec. 20, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Bodanzky, Artur no year Apr. 9, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Borchard [?], Corinne B. 1932 June 21, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Boston Symphony Orchestra 1951 Jan. 24, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Boulanger, Nadia 1937 Apr. 29, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Brooks, Mary Seymour 1931 Feb. 25, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Burgin, Richard 1939 Sept. 12, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Clarke, W.R. 1939 Mar. 28, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Coolidge Kindler 1926 May 12, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - De Lamarter, Eric 1939, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Demarest, Charles 1950 Nov. 5 - 1 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Elton, J.P. 1939 Dec. 30, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Engel, Carl 1924 June 19, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Gabrilowitsch, Ossip 1920 Mar. 2, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Galaxy Music Corp. 1941-1946, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Graves, Henry S. 1920 Feb. 2, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Hawkins [?], Warner M. 1940 Mar. 28, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Hanson, Howard 1939-1946, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Hunt, Pearson 1946 May 22, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Kirshbaum, Joseph 1939 Dec. 6, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Kroll, William 1951 June 22, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Library of Congress 1951, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Low, A. Augustus 1946 May 24, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - McKay, George F. 1937 Apr. 15, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Morgan, Russell V. 1932 Jan. 4, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Music Teachers' National Association 1932 Jan. 8, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Nettleton, George Henry 1946 May 17, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - New English Singers 1932 Dec.? - 1 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - New Haven Heart Association 1954 Feb. 3, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Ohioana Library 1951-1956, 4 items. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - O'Meara, Eva Judd 1960 June 20, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Peffer, Fred L. 1939 Nov. 20, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Philadelphia. Free Library 1950 May 23, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Porter, Quincy 1946 June 16, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Poynter, Horace Martin 1946 Apr. 26, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Prokosch, Mrs. E. 1932, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Reed, [?] no date, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Rogers, Burton 1950 Nov. 30, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Rubinstein, Beryl 1946 Mar. 28, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Sektberg, Willard 1937-1941, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Seymour, Charles 1936-1946, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Shepherd, Arthur 1946 Apr. 14, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Shepherd, Brooks 1958 Jan. 20, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Simonds, Bruce 1950-1951, 3 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Society for the Publication of American Music 1950-1954, 3 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Stevenson, Robert M. 1939-1946, 3 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Toledo Orchestra 1950-1951, 6 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Tuthill, Burnet C. 1939-1951, 3 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Vaughan Williams, Ralph [1935?] Apr. 14, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Voorhees, Pauline no date, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Walter, Bruno 1941-1948, 7 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Westervelt, Louise St. John 1913-1915, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Wheeler, James E. 1932 Apr. 4, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Wheeler, Mary no year May 4, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Who's Who in America 1950 Jan. 3, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Works Projects Administration 1939 Oct. 28, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Yale Alumni Fund 1955 May 24, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Yale-in-China Association 1955, 2 items. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Yale University. Secretary 1936 Mar. 3, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Yale School of Music 1942 Mar. 31, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified 1940-1950, no date - 7 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - From David Stanley Smith to others, II.B
    - Balaban, Emanuel 1929 Nov. 18, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Black, Frank J. 1933 Oct. 31, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Burgin, Richard 1939 Sept. 13, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Cross, Wilbur L. 1932 Oct. 12, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Hoover Institute [1949] - 1 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Kneisel, Franz 1915 Apr. 12, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - New Haven Journal-Courier 1942 Dec. 8, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Noss, Luther 1949 Jan. 27, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Spivacke, Harold no year June 29, 1 item. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Letters from David Stanley Smith and others to H. Earle Johnson 1934-1942, 9 items. (Box 33, Folder 10)
      Gift of Mr. Johnson, 1968 Mar 21.
- Clippings, III
  This series contains newspaper and magazine clippings concerning Smith, others, and miscellaneous subjects. They are arranged chronologically within each subseries. If a clipping was found with an item such as a letter, a note has been added to the clipping and the item. The clippings have been photocopied onto acid-free paper.
  - Concerning David Stanley Smith and His Music, III.A
    - 1912-1928, 29 items. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - 1930-1932, 12 items. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - 1933-1936, 26 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - 1937-1939, 17 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - 1940, 15 items. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - 1941, 17 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - 1942, 14 items. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - 1943-1956, 19 items. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - no date, 16 items. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Concerning Others, III.B
    - 1919-1963, 11 items. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, III.C
    - 1889-1944, 5 items. (Box 34, Folder 11)
- Programs, IV
  Programs concerning performances by David Stanley Smith or of his works, as well as those concerning works or performances by others.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1890-1911, 10 items. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - 1912-1913, 8 items. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - 1914-1915, 8 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - 1916-1917, 6 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - 1918-1920, 9 items. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - 1921-1922, 11 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 1923-1924, 13 items. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - 1926-1929, 12 items. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - 1930-1931, 12 items. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - 1932-1934, 23 items. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - 1935, 19 items. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - 1936, 14 items. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - 1937, 21 items. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - 1938, 15 items. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - 1939, 17 items. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - 1940, 14 items. (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - 1941, 14 items. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - 1942, 11 items. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - 1943-1944, 14 items. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - 1945-1946, 17 items. (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - 1947-1949, 10 items. (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - 1950-1953, 22 items. (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - 1954-1957, no date, 30 items. (Box 35, Folder 23)
- Photographs, V
  - Photographs of David Stanley Smith and others 1900-1941., 40 items. (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
- Works by and about David Stanley Smith, VI
  This series contains works by Smith, such as articles and lecture notes, and biographical material. The items are arranged chronologically within each subseries.
  - Works by David Stanley Smith, VI.A
    - "Modern music: a suggestion." The Yale Review, October 1922, pp. 99-109. (Box 37)
    - "The education of the average student in music." In Papers and proceedings of the Music Teachers' National Association: annual meeting... 28-30 December 1925, edited by Karl W. Gehrkens, pp. 11-19. Hartford: Music Teachers' National Association, 1926.
    - "The education of the average student in music." The Musician 31 (1926): 15. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - "The Yale School of Music." The Yale Alumni Weekly 35 (1926): 717-718. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - "The education of the average student in music." The Etude 44 (1926): 495. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - "Wagner and the modern musician." The Yale Review 15 (1926): 814-817. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - "The attitude of the teacher toward modern music." The Musician 31 (1926): 30. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - "Beethoven one hundred years after." The Yale Review 16 (1927): 445-458.
    - "A study of Horatio Parker." The Musical Quarterly 16 (1930): 153-169. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Gustave J. Stoeckel: Yale pioneer in music. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1939. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Listeners' Introductions" for 2 piano rolls:
      Chopin's Mazurka in C sharp minor... played by L. Kreutzer. A-120. (U.S.A.: Duo-Art)
      Mozart's Fantasia in D minor played by Alexander Raab. A-123. (U.S.A.: Duo-Art)
    - "Problems of choral music." Unpublished typescript. (Box 38, Folder 5)
      4 sheets, 2 copies.
    - [Lecture notes?] Unpublished pencil holograph. (Box 38, Folder 6)
      10 p.
  - Biographical material, VI.B
    - The Yale class book... 1900, edited by John W. Decrow. New Haven: Yale University, 1900. [signed by David Stanley Smith]
    - Decennial record of the class of 1900 Yale College, compiled by George N. Whittlesey. New Haven, Conn.: The Tuttle, Morehouse Taylor Co., 1912.
    - The book of the Yale pageant 21 October 1916, edited by George Henry Nettleton. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1916. (Box 39)
    - "Aeolian Hall Sunday afternoon, December 11th." Symphony Society Bulletin 15 (1921): 1. (Box 39, Folder 7)
      [2 copies]
    - Quarter-century record of the class of 1900 Yale College, edited by Lucius B. Barbour. New Haven: Published under the direction of the Class Secretaries Bureau, 1926.
    - Granniss, Lewis C. Connecticut Composers. New Haven: The Connecticut State Federation of Music Clubs, 1935.
    - "Smith, David Stanley." National Institute News Bulletin 5 (1939): 10. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Tuttle, Burnet C. "David Stanley Smith." The Musical Quarterly 28 (1942): 63-77. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Performances and publications." Yale University. Alumni Bulletin, 1942 March, p. [3] (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Osburn, Mary Hubbell. Ohio Composers and musical authors. S.l.: Mary Hubbell Osburn, 1942.
    - A collection of poems by members of the class of Yale 1900. S.l.: Privately printed for Henry 0. Havemeyer, 1945.
    - Forty-fifth anniversary record of the class of 1900 Yale 1900, edited by The Reunion Committee Henry O. Havemeyer, Chairman. Portland, Maine: The Southward-Anthoensen Press, 1946.
    - Smith, Cora Welch. David Stanley Smith: information on his compositions and ancestry. Unpublished pencil and ink manuscript, 1949 Dec. [68 p.] (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - "David Stanley Smith." Bulletin of Yale University. (Box 40, Folder 12)
      Obituary record of graduates of the undergraduate schools deceased during the year ending July 1, 1950 47 (1951): 45.
- Royalty Statements and Agreements, VII
  - Royalty statements 1908-1955, 18 items. (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Agreements between Galaxy Music Corporation and David Stanley Smith 1938 Nov-Dec, 2 items. (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Memorabilia, VIII
  - Memorabilia 1917-1952, 7 + 17 items. (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
    Includes certificates, jottings, brochures, bills, booklet, notebook, etc.
Index of Music
Adagietto Band
The aeroplane Songs
Air Keyboard
Air from Suite in D / J.S. Bach Misc
Alastor Orchestral
"Alhambra" waltzes Misc
All heaven and earth are still Choral
All ye people Choral
L'allegro and il penseroso Orchestral
Allegro giocoso, orchestra, op. 17 Orchestral
Alone Songs
An Athenian festival Orchestral
The Annunciation Misc
Anthems for men's chorus and organ Choral
Anthems on texts from the Old Testament Choral
Anthems, op. 95 Choral Choral
Anthems. Selections Choral
The apostle, orchestra, op. 92 Orchestral Orchestral
April Songs
Asahel march-two step Misc
Awake, my heart! Songs
Badinage Band
The baker-shop Songs
Ballad Choral
Ballade Chamber Misc
La belle dame Chamber
Benedic anima mea Misc
Berceuse Chamber
Bird of my lady's bower Songs
Blessed are they Choral Choral Misc
Blue, white, and gold Songs
Boulevard two-step Misc
Bow down Choral
The bracelet Choral
Cadenzas, piano Misc
Canons from Waltham Opera
Caprice, bassoon, piano, op. 50 bis Chamber
A caravan from China Choral Choral
Carnival Orchestral
Caterpillar Songs
Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54 Solo Keyboard
Charity ball twostep Misc
The Cherub Contemplation Keyboard
Chick-a-dee-dee Songs
The children's carol Misc
A child's laughter Choral
A child's thanks Choral
Choral music, women's voices Choral
Choric dance Orchestral
Choruses, op. 94 Choral
Christmas carols Misc
Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts Choral
The clock Songs
The cloudlet Choral
Clouds Keyboard
Come to these scenes of peace Choral
Come unto Me Songs Songs
Comfort Ye Choral
Compositions, band, op. 101 Band
Compositions, piano, op. 87 Keyboard Keyboard
Concert overture, op. 1, E flat major Orchestral
Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F Solo Solo Chamber
Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 86, G Solo Solo Chamber
Corydon and Thyrsis Keyboard
A cradle song Songs
"Cradle-song" Misc
Create in me Choral
Credo, orchestra, op. 83 Orchestral Keyboard
Crickets Songs
Cupid at cards Songs Songs
Daffodils - plucked! Orchestral
Dance of youth Orchestral
Danse fantastique Keyboard
The dark Choral Choral
Darkness and dawn, op. 5 Orchestral
Daybreak Choral
Death of Oedipus. Chamber
La débutante waltz Misc
The delicate air Misc
La Désespérée Keyboard
The djinns Choral
Doth not wisdom cry? Choral Choral
Dramatic fantasy Keyboard
Dramatic fantasy, piano, op. 82 Keyboard Keyboard
Eight years old Songs
Elegy Orchestral Songs
Epic poem, orchestra, op. 55 Orchestral
Evening harmonies, organ Keyboard
Evening prayer Songs
Evening song Songs Songs
Evensong and choral Keyboard
Examination tests for fellowship A.G.O. Misc
Exercises Misc
Exercises in XVIth century counterpoint Misc
"Eyes of old Yale blue" Misc
Fading lilies Orchestral
The fairies' Christmas-tree Songs
The fairies' dance Songs
The fallen star Choral
Fantasia and five-voiced fugue Keyboard
The far-off curfew Keyboard
Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 Solo Solo Chamber Chamber
Flight Keyboard
The flower of beauty Songs Songs
Flowers, orchestra, op. 52 Orchestral
Four pieces (string orchestra) Orchestral
The four winds Choral
The Frogs Opera
Fugato on a canto fermo of Cherubini Keyboard
Fugue(s) Keyboard
The garden Orchestral
The garden of Prosperine Choral Choral
Gavotte Misc
Gigue Keyboard
Go not, happy day Choral
God is our refuge Choral
God our life Choral
Gold and purple Songs
The golden age, op. 40 Orchestral
Grant to us, Lord Choral
Great peace have they Choral Choral
Greek dance Orchestral
Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1 Keyboard
A group of lyrics Choral Choral
Haidenröslein Orchestral
Harold Opera Opera
He that dwelleth Choral
Hear, o Lord Choral
Hippolytus Opera Opera
Hoppy-toad Songs
Houses Songs
Humoresque Keyboard
I dwell in the high and Holy place Choral
I wandered lonely Misc
I will greatly rejoice Choral
I will lift up mine eyes Choral
I will praise Thee with my whole heart Choral
Ianthe Keyboard
Idyl - the death of Daphnis Orchestral
If only thou art true Songs
I'm the hottest nigger on the map Misc
Impressions, orchestra, op. 40b Orchestral
In Gethsemane Songs
In praise of the queen of the shepherds Songs
Iphigenia in Tauris Opera
Jack-in-the-pulpit Songs
Jack-o'-lantern Songs
Jesu, fair flow'r of Mary Choral
Jesum omnes agnoscite Choral
Jesus and the children Songs
Juvenilia Misc
Katy-did Songs
The lady Alice Songs
The lady of the lambs Songs
L'allegro and il penseroso Orchestral
Lament for Antigone Chamber
Last night Songs
Laziness Songs
Le soir Songs
Let my cry come Choral Choral
Let the words Choral
Little songs Songs Songs
A little while Choral Choral
The Logos Choral Choral
The Lord is in His Holy Temple Choral
The Lord is my light Choral Choral
The Lord is my shepherd Choral Choral
The Lord reigneth Choral Choral
Love Thee? Songs
Love's music Songs
Lullaby Songs
Lux et veritas Choral Choral
Lyric poems, violin, piano, op. 64 Chamber
Madonna Songs
Madrigals, op. 35. No. 6-7 Choral
The march of the three kings Misc
Masque Orchestral
Matin song Choral
Medea Chamber
Meditation Songs
Meeres-stille Keyboard Keyboard
Melodies, orchestra, op. 50 Orchestral Orchestral
Melody, organ Keyboard
Memorial ode Choral
Merrymount, op. 36 Opera Opera Opera
The message Songs Songs
Mild is the parting year Songs
Morning Choral Songs
Morning song Choral Choral
Most glorious night Choral
Mother, I cannot mind my wheel Songs
My little birch-tree Songs
My pretty rose tree Songs
My sheep wandered through all the mountains Choral
My Sue Misc
Nine years old Songs Songs
1929 - A satire Orchestral
Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1 Orchestral Orchestral Keyboard
No rest for Thy head Misc
Nocturnes Keyboard
Nod Songs
Noël nouvlet Misc
Noël to honor Mary Mother Misc
Now dawning glows the day of days Choral Choral
Nunc dimittis Choral
Nuptial prayer Songs
O Lord, from whom all things Choral
Oatmeal Songs
The ocean Choral
Ode for Commencement Day Choral Choral
Office, Holy Communion Choral Choral
Old Susan Songs
"Olympian" two-step Misc
Olympus Orchestral
On a sunshine holiday Keyboard
Oracle Chamber
Oresteiad Opera Opera
Ouverture joyeuse, op. 11 Orchestral
Ouverture sérieuse, op. 12 Orchestral
Pan Choral Choral Choral
The papoose Songs
Part-songs, mixed voices, op. 34 Choral Choral Choral Choral
Part-songs, women's voices, op. 35 Choral
The parting hour Songs
Partita classica, organ, op. 70, no. 2 Keyboard
Passepied Keyboard
The passing of Oedipus, orchestra, op. 98 Orchestral
Peace Songs
Peace (Teasdale) Songs
The pensive violin Orchestral
Persistent theme Orchestral
Phantom troops Orchestral
Piano piece Keyboard Misc
Pièce grotesque Keyboard
Pieces, string orchestra, op. 89 Orchestral
The pine-wood Songs
Poem in three parts Chamber
A poem of youth, orchestra, op. 47 Orchestral
Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3 Keyboard Keyboard
Poem ... written in time of war Keyboard
Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 bis Chamber
Polly Songs Misc
Portraits Songs
Praeludium triumphale, violin, piano op. 75 bis Chamber Chamber
Prelude and Fugue Keyboard
Prelude and offertory, organ Keyboard